已经概略的讨论了
so now that we've had a high level discussion
堆中在 tcache 下层的机制
of what occurs deeper in the heap pass tcache
现在来详细讲解这个流程图
let's step through that flow chart step by step
详细介绍各种 bin
and talk about each bin
他们为什么存在
why they're there
他们的工作原理
how they work
以及他们的作用
and what they do
tcache 过后的第一站是 fast bins
so our first stop after tcache is fast bins
fast bins 和 tcache 起着类似的作用
now fast bins and tcache serve a similar role
它们都是缓存层
they're both caching layers
但他们的作用
but what they do
以及存在原因实际上是不同的
and the reason that they exist is in fact different
fast bins 早于 tcache
fast bins predates tcache
相较于堆，tcache是最近才有的
tcache is actually a pretty recent development as far as heap
它在libc的最近几个版本中才出现了
it's been around in a couple versions of libc now
tcache 中的 t 代表线程
now recall that the t in tcache stands for thread
tcache是一个线程缓存层
a tcache is a thread caching layer
每当访问 tcache 的下层
whenever the heap is accessed deeper than tcache
都会涉及到一个堆全局锁
there is a global heap lock that has to occur
所以添加 tcache 的原因
and so the reason tcache was added
是为了减少多个线程对堆同时访问
was to prevent contention from multiple threads trying to access the heap at the same time
因为访问堆需要对整个堆加锁以确保
because the whole heap needs to lock to make sure that
多个线程申请内存时，堆状态可信
there is a consistent state when multiple processes are trying to obtain allocations from the heap
而 tcache 使每个线程都有单独的缓存
and so tcache sits as a layer where every thread gets its own cache
这缓解了
so that should alleviate the contention
多个线程访问堆下层的竞争情况
of multiple threads trying to access deeper into the heap
fast bins也是一个缓存层
now fast bins is a caching layer as well
但是fast bins是堆本身的缓存层
but fast bins is a caching layer for the heap itself
就设计而言
as far as design
fast bin与 tcache 非常相似
fast bins is very similar to tcache
它也是一个单链表
it's a singly linked list
也使用安全链接
it uses safe linking
fast bins和 tcache 有一些不同之处
now some of the things that are different about fast bins versus tcache
fast bin 链表没有长度限制
fast bin lists can grow to an unlimited length
tcache 链表最多有7个chunk
you'll recall that tcache lists have a maximum length of 7 chunks
当释放第8个相同大小的chunk时
if you free an 8th chunk to tcache
它不会缓存到 tcache 中
it will not cache it
它会被传递到tcache下层
that free chunk will get past deeper into the heap
现在如果这个chunk的大小达到0x80字节(新ppt已改)
now in the event that chunk is up to 88 bytes in size
它大小适当
it's reasonably small
它可能因为tcache满了绕过 tcache
that chunk may bypass tcache because tcache is full
如果大小合适，它可能会被放入fast bin
and that chunk may end up here in fast bin if it's the correct size
fast bins最多只能容纳0x80B的chunk
now fast bins only accommodates up to 88 bytes
那 tcache 呢
what is tcache hold
tcache 最大可缓存 1032字节的 chunk
well tcache holds up to about 1,032 bytes for the chunk size
fast bins 只缓存很小的内存
and so fast bins caches very small allocations kind of like
适用于需要频繁malloc和free的程序
scratch malloc and frees that a program may rapidly need to do
而且malloc的内存使用时间很短
but they're probably not going to hang on to
所以对于堆
and so it makes sense for the heap
缓存一些常用的小chunk是有用的
to hang onto some of these extremely common small allocations
他们被缓存在fast bins中
and so that gets cached in the fast bins
fast bins 是如何缓存这些小的分配的呢
now how does fast bins hang onto these small allocations
上节课提到了 P位和合并
one of the things that I mentioned the prior lecture was this P bit and consolidation
我们会把小chunk 合并起来
and we want to take these small chunks and combine them
生成一些更大的chunk
and rebuild these larger chunks
这样多次内存分配后，不会产生大量内存碎片
so that way we can service more requests without getting fragmented
fast bins通过不清除P位来防止合并
well fast bins prevents consolidation by not clearing the p bit
所以当chunk被缓存到fast bin
so when a chunk is freed and placed into fast bin
后一个chunk的P位不会被清除
the P bit for the next chunk is not cleared
所以在堆的下层机制
so from the heap's internal mechanism
它并不知道这些chunk被释放了
it does not see these chunks as truly free
通过不清除 P位
that p bit by not being cleared
防止 fast bins 中的chunk被合并
prevents the chunks that are in Fast Bin from being consolidated
fast bins 和 tcache的差异中有趣的一点是
now one of the kind of interesting things about fast bins compared to tcache
你可以对 tcache 利用双重释放漏洞
one of the things we saw with tcache was that you can perform a double free exploit
tcache 检查双重释放时
but tcache will check when you attempt to perform a double free
会检查对应链表中的所有chunk
against every entry of that size
tcache中该大小对应链表的所有chunk
every entry in the tcache list for the size of the chunk that's being freed
但是 fast bins 可以无限长
but fast bins can grow to an unlimited length
所以从性能的角度来看，为了防止双重释放
and so it would actually be prohibitive from a performance standpoint
每次调用free，都去遍历一个无限长的单链表，是不现实的
to track a singly linked list of an unlimited length for double free every time free is called
且会放到fast bins的，都是些经常free的
and the chunks that are freed into fast bins are the type of chunks that get freed often
所以fast bins的free要高效
so we want the act of freeing to some too fast bins to be efficient to be performant
fast bins的chunk的双重释放检查
and so the double free check when a chunk is freed into fast bins
只看最近被放入的那一个chunk
only looks at the top chunk the most recently freed chunk that was placed into fast bins
这意味着会有双重释放绕过的情况
this has implications for when a double free scenario can sneak into the heap
和我们在tcache中看到的非常相似
so very similar to what we saw with tcache
fast bins采用单链表
the fast bins are a singly linked list
fast bins中针对各大小的bin都有一个头指针
fast bins consist of a head pointer for every size that is in fastbin
头指针指向最近释放的chunk
the fastbin head pointer points to the most recently freed chunk
如果free时要放到fast bins中
so when we need to free something into fast bins
只需修改，被释放chunk的next，为头指针的值
all we have to do is update the next pointer of the newly freed chunk to the current head
然后将头指针指向当前释放的chunk
and then update the head to the newly freed chunk
这与tcache非常相似
this works very much like tcache
那当 malloc 时
now what happens if we're trying to malloc something
申请大小大于 0x80 字节呢
but it's going to be larger than this 88 bytes
那就不会在 fast bin中找了
well then it doesn't make sense to look at these fast bins
要查看另一种 bin
we're going to have to look in another bin
因为fast bin中最大只有 0x80字节的chunk
because the biggest thing that could be in fast bins is a chunk of 88 bytes
下一个要找的位置是 small bins
so the next place to consider would be the small bins
small bins是一个双链表
now small bins are a doubly linked list
这就有点复杂了
so it's going to be a bit more complicated
但是small bins有一个优点
but one of the advantages of small bins
就是它能够合并
is the small bins are capable of consolidating
small bin存在的原因是能提高访问效率
so the reason we have these small bins is to be able to provide performance access
因为这里的 bin的大小是固定的
because these bins are a constant size
我们不需要从里面筛选
we don't have to sift through these
如果我们想要256字节内存
if we want something that is say 256 bytes
在small bin中有直接指向256字节chunk的指针
there is a pointer in the small bins to chunks of size exactly 256 bytes
bin中chunk大小相同，最大可达1024字节（64位机器）
so the bins are a constant size for every size up to 1024 bytes
访问时间是固定的,O(1)
so we get that constant access time
我们可以快速访问
we get that fast access
给定一个大小，立马就知道上哪个bin中取
because we can say a size and we know immediately where to look
与fast bins不同的是
but unlike fast bins
small bins中的chunk能够合并
the small bins chunks are capable of consolidating
被释放到small bins里的，后一个chunk的P位会被清除
that P bit is cleared for things that are freed into the small bins
small bins 看起来是什么样呢？
so what does a small bin list look like
small bins中同样各bin中有一个头指针
well small bins very similarly have a head pointer for every constant size
头指针将指向一个chunk
that head pointer will point to a chunk
这些chunk 不再只有一个next指针
now these chunks instead of just having a next pointer
他们有前向和后向指针
these have a forward and back
因为是双链表
because they're doubly linked
所以能遍历回到chunk1
now a consequence of this is you can navigate these chunks and get back to chunk 1
只要不停往前，或往后
by calling forward forward forward or back back back
最终都会回到原来的位置
and you'd end up right back where you were
在这个例子中只有三个chunk
in this example because there's only three chunks
但实际上永远不需要这么做
but in practice you never need to navigate these lists like that
用双链表的原因是
the reason that these lists are doubly linked
能方便高效地删除节点
is to allow for very easy removal of items from the list via that unlinked process
这有点违反直觉
so kind of counterintuitively
增加链表的遍历能力
by adding more abilities to navigate the list
反倒不需要遍历链表了
we never have to actually navigate the list
如果我们调用malloc
so what happens if we call malloc
请求chunk的大小
and the chunk that I want that I'm requesting
大于fast bin的最大值 0x80字节
is going to be larger than the 88 bytes that could be found in fast bins
也大于small bin的最大值 1024字节
and it's larger than the 1024 bytes that could be found in small bins
或者这是第一次调用malloc呢
or what if this is the very first allocation
这些bin里还没缓存chunk
so there's nothing that's been put in these bins yet
没有释放任何chunk到这些bin中
we haven't freed anything into the bins
接下来会发生什么
well where what happens next
接下来将合并 fast bins
well the next step is to consolidate the fast bins
我知道你在想什么
and I know what you're thinking like
等等，你刚刚不是说fast bin是不合并的吗
wait a minute here you just said fast bins aren't consolidated
fast bin 的P位一直是1
fast bins have the P bit set
这没错
well this is true
但是fast bin是一个缓存层
but fast bins is a caching layer right
如果我们需要的都缓存在这里
if all we needed were things that could be easily cached here
或者都在 small bins 范围内
and then all we needed were things that were in the small bins
需要的chunk都小于1024字节
so things that were smaller than that 1024 bytes
那就不会触发fast bins合并
we don't need to worry about consolidating
因为我们没打算申请一个大的chunk
because we aren't trying to produce a large chunk
malloc不用返回一个大的chunk
malloc isn't asking for large chunks
还要等待合并触发条件
so let's wait on consolidation
但当 malloc 被调用
but as soon as malloc is called
请求的chunk大小 大于1024字节
requesting a chunk of greater size than 1024 bytes
我们就要清理fast bin
we're going to clear the fast bin
会遍历他们
we're going to go through all of those items
清除相应的P位
and clear the P bit or the corresponding p bit
这使 fast bins chunk发生合并成为可能
this is going to allow for consolidation of those fast bin chunks to occur
总结一下
so to recap
如果malloc的chunk大小超过1024字节
if a chunk is mallocd over 1024 bytes in size
说明程序需要大的chunk
then the program is asking for a large chunk
我们不希望堆中出现内存碎片
we don't want the heap to be fragmented
所以对于fast bins中的缓存
and so all of those quick caching things that we are doing in Fast Bin
我们会对其遍历，使之能合并
we're going to go through and make it so that those are capable of consolidating
这样可以防止内存碎片
this should prevent fragmentation
fast bins中的合并也可能发生在 free 中
now this consolidating of the fast bins can also occur when free is called
这个65KB是
and this is
如果你看一下这里链接的源代码
if you look at the source code which is linked here
注释中甚至说了这个65KB是按经验选的
the source code comments even say that this value is just like chosen heuristically
当释放一个chunk时
but if a chunk is freed
这个大小是这个常量
and there is a magic number here
它大约是65KB，65536B
but it's about 65 kilobytes in size
如果释放的是一个大于 65KB的chunk
if a chunk larger than 65 kilobytes is freed
这也将触发fast bin中的清理和合并
this will also trigger fast bins to clear out and begin consolidating
所以，如果malloc大于1024字节
so if a chunk is mallocd that is greater than 1024 bytes in size
fast bins 会清空
the fast bins will clear out
并使那些chunk能合并
and those chunks are able to be consolidated
不是说会立马合并
it doesn't mean that they will
记住，合并需要的
because remember consolidation requires that
不只是fast bins中chunk是空闲的
not only the chunks in fast bins are free
还需要这些chunk周围有空闲chunk
but also a chunk immediately after or before in memory are free
因此，不保证立马会合并
and so the clearing and consolidating doesn't guarantee consolidation
只保证fast bin中的chunk有被合并的可能
it guarantees the possibility of consolidating these fast bins
会清空 fast bin 中的所有缓存记录
it's going remove all of the entries from fast bins
并保证他们有被合并的可能
and allow the possibility of consolidation
我们已经完成了这一步
so we've done that step
我们已经尽可能地合并了fast bin
we've consolidated the fast bins as well as possible
下一步是什么
what's the next step
流程图中下一步是查找unsorted bin
the next step on the flow chart is to look at this unsorted bin
这个ppt中没画
now I don't have it here on the slides
但上一节课中 free流程图里有
but there's a similar flow chart from the prior lecture on free
当有超过fast bins 大小范围的
and free flow chart basically says if there's anything larger than fast bins
并最终放入 unsorted bin的chunk
then it ends up in the unsorted bin
unsorted bin 就是
and the I said that the unsorted bin was just kind of
释放后不想立马处理的一些chunk
this pile of stuff that we freed that we don't want to deal with
如果 malloc 一个大于1024B的chunk
well if malloc is called and we need something larger than 1024 bytes
请求chunk不在 small bin范围中
so it can't be found in the small bin
这时就需要遍历unsorted bin这一堆
it's time to go through that pile of junk that we've been putting off
这就是unsorted bin
and that is what the unsorted bin is
unsorted bin 是一个双链表
so the unsorted bin is a doubly linked list
unsorted bin中装的可能是 large或small chunk
the unsorted bin holds values that could have been large bin or small bin
unsorted bin中chunk都大于0x80B
so any the unsorted bin holds chunks greater than 88 bytes in size
它们无法直接装入fast bins中
it's anything that couldn't immediately get cacheed in fast bins
此时如果malloc被调用
now when malloc is called
一直走到这一步
if we make it all the way through to this step
将会开始在 unsorted bin中查找
what occurs is the unsorted bin chunks start getting checked
假设 unsorted bin 中有一个 100B的chunk
so let's say the unsorted bin has a chunk size of 100
现在malloc 一个 80B的chunk
and I'm trying to malloc something that is 80 bytes
需要一个80字节的chunk
I need an 80 byte chunk
unsorted bin开头的这个100B chunk
could 100 byte chunk that i grabbed that was at the beginning of the unsorted bin
能满足要求吗
can that satisfy the requirement
答案是可以的
the answer is yes
从unsorted bin中拿到的这个100B chunk 可以满足需求
the chunk that I grabbed from the unsorted bin is big enough to satisfy the requirement
就将其分割
we'll cut it off we'll split it
然后返回切下来的80B的chunk
we'll make it work and we'll return that 80 byte chunk
就是直接从 unsorted bin开头取一个chunk
so we're just grabbing whatever happened to be here in the unsorted bin
然后看是否满足要求
and say hey can we make this work
那如果是malloc 一个大的chunk
now what happens if that malloc request is for something large
假设malloc 一个3000B的chunk
say we're trying to malloc 3000 bytes
从 unsorted bin 开头取的
well the first thing that gets grabbed from the unsorted bin
还是100B的chunk
could still be that 100 byte chunk
能从100B中分出一个3000B的chunk吗
can I make a 3,000 byte chunk from 100 byte chunk
答案是否定的
the answer is no
好吧，有一个100B的chunk
and so we have to say okay well now I have this hundred byte chunk
满足不了malloc的需求
so it doesn't satisfy the malloc
我们要把它放到应该去的位置
we're going to go put it where it goes
会把它放到对应的 small bin中
so we'll put it in the correct small bin
因为，small bins最大可以管理 1024B的chunk
because remember small bins handle chunks up to 1024 in size
接下来再从unsorted bin中取一个chunk
so then we're going to grab the next chunk from the unsorted bin list
然后看看它
and we're going to look at it
是否足够malloc要的3000B
and okay is this large enough for a 3000 chunk to be allocated to return from malloc
如果不行
if the answer is no
就把它放到对应的small 或 large bin中
we put it in the appropriate small or large bin
如果可以
if the answer is yes
就返回它（可能是一部分）
we make it work  and just return what we found from the unsorted bin
unsorted bin 是一个双链表
so the unsorted bin list again is a doubly linked list
然而，与small bins不同的是，它只有一个bin
however unlike small bins the unsorted bin is just one pointer
只有一个头指针，这个双链表中放了所有unsorted bin的chunk
it is just a pointer where this is everything goes everything goes into the unsorted bin
这里没有依据大小的索引
and so we don't have fast access here
如果你还记得的话，small bins中每个大小都有对应的头指针
if you'll recall these small bins had a unique head pointer for constant sizes
这样，当我们需要一个256B的chunk时
and that allowed us to say I need something that's 256 bytes
我立马就能知道对应链表在哪里
I know where that list is
在small bins里有一个指针
it's in the small bins there's one pointer
指向 256B的chunk的链表
that pointer has the 256 byte allocations
如果这个链表是空的
but if there weren't any there
我们就去unsorted bin中找
okay we go through this unsorted bin pile
然后我们开始筛选
and we'll start sifting through this
如果unsorted bin中取出来的未满足条件
and if what we grab doesn't meet our requirement
那么我们就把它放到对应的small bin 或 large bin
then we will file it away into the correct small or large bin
所以unsorted bin 是一个缓存层
so unsorted bin acts as kind of a caching layer or lazy layer
位于 small bins 和 large bins 前
in front of these small and large bins
chunk 不会直接放到 small bins 或 large bins中
chunks never go directly to these small or large bins
当一个chunk 被 free 时
when a chunk is freed
它最后可能会到 small bins 或 large bins 中
that could end up in the small or large bins
但它首先会放到 unsorted bin中
it will always go to the unsorted bin first
这提供了一个机会
this provides a chance
不管之前放到 unsorted bin的是大还是小 chunk
for whatever it was that we happen to put there
都能拿来重用
to just get grabbed and reused
遍历完了unsorted bin
so we've gone through the unsorted bin
但我们要找的是非常大的chunk
but we're looking for something really large
如果malloc一个3000B的chunk
what if this malloc request is for 3,000 bytes
fast bins中没有3000B的chunk
there's nothing that's going to be 3,000 bytes in fast bin
small bins中也没有3000B的chunk
there's nothing that's going to be 3,000 bytes in small bins
遍历完unsorted bin（也没有）
we've gone through all of the junk that's been freed into the unsorted bin
之后上哪儿找？
where is the next place to look
下一处要找的位置是 large bins
well the next place to look is the large bins
large bins是一个双链表
large bins are a doubly linked list
然而，large bins中bin里chunk大小不是固定的
however large bins are not of constant size
large bins里每个bin管理一个大小范围
the large bins consist of a size range
这意味着bin中的 chunk 需要排序
now that means that the chunks in the bin need to be sorted
按大小，从大到小排序
and they're sorted by size with the largest chunk first
large bins有意思的一点是
now one of the interesting things about large bins is
在讨论堆元数据时讲过
I mentioned in the kind of heap metadata discussion
chunk有一个fd_nextsize和一个bk_nextsize指针
that chunks have a fd_nextsize and a bk_nextsize pointer
至少可以有这两指针
or at least they can have these values
在large bins中会用到这两指针
these pointers are used when trying to resolve large bins
可以在该bin大小范围内切换到一个相邻大小
because this provides the ability to check a bin and if were in a range
现在需要该bin大小范围中较大的chunk
and I need something that's on the upper end of that bin range
但结果该bin中的chunk
but it turns out all of the chunks that are in the bin
都集中在小端
are on the smaller side of the range
我需要跳到附近更大的大小范围
and what I really need to do is I need to jump up to the next bin size
我需要去那个更大的大小范围中找
I need to find something that is in the next largest range
找到目标victim，分割出需要的大小
and then split that chunk to create the size that I need
这个功能通过binmap数组实现
and that is what the fd_nextsize and bk_nextsize pointers do
binmap数组的元素类型是uint32，一个元素可管理32个bin
they provide pointers to the next chunk that is in the larger bin size or bin range
注意large bins中bin对应的chunk大小是范围，而不是常量
because remember the sizes on large bins are ranges not constant sizes
这有一个large bins的例子
so here's an example of large bins
可以看到，large bins仍然是一个双链表
you'll notice that large bins are still a doubly linked list
对于元数据和链表，格式还是一样的
they still follow that same format as far as the metadata and the list itself
然而，large bins的不同之处
however one of the things that's different about large bins
在于这些头指针
has to do with these head pointers
这些头指针还是指向双链表
we still have head pointers that point into the list
然而，双链表对应的chunk大小是范围，而不是常量
however the head pointers correspond to ranges of sizes not a constant range
large bins中最小的大小范围是 512~576B
now the smallest of the large bins corresponds to sizes of 512 to 576 bytes
bins一般聚集在小的那边
now the bins themselves are clustered to the smaller side
因为一般很少malloc特别大的内存
because large allocations are pretty rare
所以large bins中前32个bin步长只有64字节
so the first 32 bins of the large bins only stride 64 bytes
所以能看到范围：512~576、 576~640、 640~704
that's why we see 512 to 576 then 576 to 640 640 to 704
可以，以64B为步长，走32次
we could continue this 32 times striding by 64 bytes
那么 binmap数组 有什么用呢
so what was the purpose of this bk_nextsize with this fd_nextsize
如果需要一个chunk大小为
well what if I wanted something that was exactly
假设：630B
let's say 640 er 600 let's do 630 bytes
需要一个这么大的chunk
and that's the size chunk that I need
显然会在第二个bin里找
well I would look in this second bin right
会在 576~640B这个范围中找
I would be looking for chunks of size 576 to 640
630B正好在这里
630 falls right in there
但如果该bin中所有chunk都是580B呢
but what if every chunk that's in here is exactly 580 bytes in size
我在合适的bin找了
well I went to the correct bin
想要的chunk是630B的
I wanted something that was 630
在这个包含了630B的合适bin中找了
and so I went to the right bin that had the range that included 630
但如果这个链表的第一个chunk小于 630B
but if the first chunk there is smaller when I first accessed the list
如果第一个chunk小于630B
if that first chunk is smaller than 630
我可以通过binmap数组
I can go to and use the fd_nextsize or bk_nextsize
找到一个更大的最接近目标大小的非空bin
to jump up to the next larger free chunk in all of the large bins
这样调用方不需要主动依次检查
and so I don't have to go and check
576~640B，640~704B
576 to 640 then check 640 to 704
哦，那个bin是空的
oh that one was empty
然后再主动查看右边的
then go and check the next one right
我们不需要主动去遍历所有的大小范围
I don't have to iterate through all of these size ranges
只要去我需要的chunk所在的范围找一次
I go to the range that I need
看看里面有没有
I see if there's anything there is
如果有符合要求的
if what is there meets the size requirement
很好
great
如果没有符合要求的
if what is in that range doesn't meet the size requirement that is needed
就用binmap找到合适的bin（没找到就去top了）
I can use these fd_nextsize and bk_nextsize pointer
然后跳到合适的bin
to jump up to the next free size class
这就是为什么需要binmap数组
and that's why those pointers are needed
那如果malloc要的大小
so what happens if the chunk that is needed from malloc
不在large bins里
the size isn't in the large bins
这是完全有可能的
and that's totally reasonable
进程启动时总有这种情况
this happens all the time when a program starts
因为还没free过，这些bin都是空的
because we haven't freed stuff into all of these bins
或malloc的太大，需要用mmap
or is the allocation so large that we need to mmap
这是接下来的问题
it would be the next question
chunk可能是用mmap获取的
well a chunk may get mmapped
应该还记得有个M位
you'll recall that there was that m bit
有A、M和P标志位
we said there was an A an M and a P flags
这些标志位于size的最低3个有效位
and these flags were in the least significant bits of the size value
M标志位表示chunk是否是通过mmap获取的
that m flag indicates that an allocation was mmapped
如果一个chunk特别大
so if an allocation is exceptionally large
对于动态分配器来说，mmap一个内存页更合理
it may make more sense to the dynamic allocator to mmap its own pages for the allocation
相反如果malloc的大小合适
alternatively if it is a reasonable allocation size
可以从wilderness中切一块下来
we can create the chunk from the wilderness
wilderness是一大片内存，表示所有未使用过的堆内存
recall that the wilderness is a giant chunk that represents all free heap memory
起始位置有一chunk
there is a giant chunk at the beginning
被称为top
that's referred to as top
底部还有一个chunk被称为 bottom
and then there's a chunk at the end that is bottom
所以末尾有两个chunk
so you have two chunks at the end
其它chunk可以被合并到top中
and so things can consolidate up into the top
比如分配的第一个chunk可以合并到top
like the very first chunk that gets allocated could get consolidated into the top
还有，wilderness
and then there's the wilderness
它是所有未分配的内存空间
which is everything that has all of the memory space that has yet to be allocated
malloc时
and so when we try and malloc something
如果所有bin中都没有合适的chunk
and there's no chunk that satisfies that need in any of the bins
我们可以用wilderness创建一块
we can create it from the wilderness
wilderness是在堆末尾的一片巨大内存
which is just a giant chunk that represents everything
表示所有还未分配的内存
that hasn't been allocated at the end of the heap
这大概是malloc时会发生的所有步骤
and so that is kind of the series of steps that can occur when malloc is called